BRUNO SPOLIDORIO

ABOUT ME

Over the past 5 years as Front-end Developer, I have developed, and launched customized, highly responsive applications, websites and e-commerce solutions using advanced technologies. In addition, I have consistently met client expectations and project milestones while working effectively in deadline-driven environments.

EXPERIENCE

Mindera, Portugal (remote) - Frontend Developer

MAY 2022 - Now

- Leveraged React.js/Next.js and TypeScript to architect an intuitive user interface that intuitively visualizes complex information.
- Ensured code reliability through rigorous testing using Jest, guaranteeing a polished and bug-free end product.
- Elevated user engagement by implementing Fluent UI to deliver a sleek, consistent, and modern design.
- Handled data using cutting edge libraries such as Recoil/Redux.
- Implementation of an in-house UI components library Styled-Components and Storybook

Devoteam, Portugal (remote) — Frontend Developer

JUL 2021 - MAY 2022

- Development of platforms using React with Typescript and Redux
- Implementation of an in-house UI components library using Material UI + Styled Components - documented with Storybooks

FRN Cubo, Brazil (remote) - Frontend Developer

AUG 2019 - JUL 2021

- Responsible for the development and operations of Shopify projects, template update, development of a customizable template, private and public Apps.
- Working as part of the evolution team, developing for the VTEX platform.

Freelancer (remote) - Data analyst

2013 - 2020

 Responsible for providing feedback on search engine results, measuring the relevance and usefulness of web pages, special content result blocks, smart personal assistant, voice search, mobile phone request and videos in connection with predefined queries, providing comparative analysis of search engine result sets and other techniques at companies like Google, Facebook and Microsoft.

World Informática, Piracicaba - Brazil - IT Manager

2004 - 2013

 Responsible for the company's IT sector, managing internal, external and remote services. Acting as infrastructure and network planner for micro, small and medium-sized companies.

SKILLS

- TypeScript
- React.js
- Next.js
- Redux
- Styled-components
- JavaScript
- HTML5
- CSS

- VS CODE
- INSOMNIA
- GIT

EDUCATION

Autodidact

2019 - 2020

Self-taught in programming focused on Frontend development using JavaScript / TypeScript, React, HTML and CSS.

Liffey College - English (intermediate)

2014 - 2015

Intensive English language course together with 1 year exchange in Dublin.

FIEC - Programming Technician

2004 - 2006

Course focused on software development and database.